Ravin Vasudev

Dubai, UAE +971 56 924 5302 ravinvasudev@gmail.com

Software developer with 11 years of robust experience in software design and development, looking for a long-term career working with a team of smart and motivated people, where I can experience new technologies, enrich my career, and add value for users and business.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Solution Architect

MAY 2017 - CURRENT

Omnix International LLC, Dubai

Omnix is UAE's leading technology solutions provider, serving telecommunications, government and other private sectors. I continued to work on Etisalat projects upon payroll migration program between the two companies.

- Decoupled Etisalat's complex architecture into multiple loosely coupled services. It allows
 clients to integrate with specific services to support their business scenarios, bringing down
 the time investment and integration complexities.
- Developed RESTful interfaces integrated by multiple frontends (web portal, self care kiosk, business centers etc.) to enable customers to renew mobile account registration with convenience.

Technical Lead AUG 2014 - MAY 2017

Etisalat Software Solutions Pvt Ltd, Dubai

Etisalat is UAE's largest telecommunications service provider and world's 14th largest mobile network operator with a customer base of 167 million.

- Developed Spring Boot based REST service integrated by company-wide systems to send SMS and Email notifications to customers. The service was designed to handle sending 100 thousand messages a day. It also included traceability and reporting features which made it easier for contact center employees to address customers' queries.
- Developed a solution to log various customer interactions from multiple channels and built a management system for contact center to retrieve historical view to address customer queries. This significantly improved the customers' complaint resolution time.
- Revamped legacy SMS, USSD and IVR administration web portal to reduce service configuration time from 30 to 10 minutes and enhanced performance, convenience and usability.
- Received "Etisalat Hero" award twice for exemplary performance.

Senior Solution Integrator

FEB 2012 - JUL 2014

Ericsson India Global Services Pvt Ltd, India

Ericsson is the world's leading provider of software, services and information & communications technology to telecom operators in 180 countries.

 Worked on integrating Ericsson's revenue driven PrePaid Charging System with AT&T Billing System to bring subscriber billing, administration and management features to AT&T Mobility (ATTM) platform.

- Added hybrid features to ATTM platform that provide subscribers with the flexibility to manage mobile usage and payment methods. It allows subscribers to use postpay and prepay modes on the same account.
- Wrote multiple adapters for Amdocs Cramer system to process network and inventory data.

Senior Software Engineer

MAR 2009 - FEB 2012

Digivision Entertainment Pvt Ltd, India

A subsidiary of HFCL Group, India's major telecom equipment manufacturer and solutions provider offering IPTV and telephone services.

- Built consumer services for IPTV system like Facebook, Gmail, Twitter and other services.
- Enhanced user experience by developing multi-tap functionality and search feature on IPTV.
- Reduced bandwidth consumption by upto 80% by implementing multicast-shut feature when broadcast is not in use.

Software Engineer

APR 2007 - MAR 2009

Aithent Technologies Pvt Ltd, India

Aithent creates regulatory compliance management solutions for financial, healthcare, government and insurance organizations around the globe.

- Developed application for insurance agents to take online courses.
- Developed an aggregator platform for B2B customers to provide licensing information.
- Developed a wiki-based portal for knowledge sharing within the company.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages

Java, J2EE, SQL

Frameworks

Spring with Boot, MVC, Data, Cloud, Hibernate, JPA, JAX-WS, JAX-RS, JUnit

Tools

Eclipse, Maven, GIT, GitHub, JIRA, BitBucket, Postman, SOAP UI

Concepts

Agile software development, Microservices Architecture, Object Oriented Programming, Data Structures, Design Patterns, High Availability & Scaling, Caching

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Information Technology

JUL 2003 - JUL 2006

Beant College of Engineering & Technology, Gurdaspur

Diploma in Computer Engineering

JUN 2000 - MAY 2003

Thapar Polytechnic, Patiala